

CURRICULUM VITAE

Mr. Raymond Vandy

Therapist in Health City, cognitive behavioural therapist, psychodynamic Counsellor and behavioural couple therapy practitioner-trainee.

Health City, Davenport House, 16 Pepper Street, Canary Wharf, London E14 9RP. Tel: 0333 800 3006, 0333 789 0012. Email: info@healthcity.org.uk/

Introduction

I have been working in the Care sector since September 1995. I have worked in a variety of settings including The Elderly, People with Learning Disabilities, People suffering from Mental Health and Substance Abuse problems and with Refugees. I have enhanced my career by successfully completing various training courses which I have listed below. I am a strong supporter of promoting the rights of people I meet by treating them with empathy and on an individual basis.

I completed a BSc Hons Degree in Psychodynamic Counselling and Cognitive Behaviour Therapy. I also completed a Foundation Degree Short term Psychodynamic Counselling and Cognitive Behaviour Therapy and I have successfully gained accreditation status with the British Association of Counsellors and Psychotherapists.

Education

June 19 – Date Behavioural Couple Therapy for Alcohol Dependence Practitioner Training.

Tavistock NHS Trust, London.

March 2017 - July 2018 BSc Psychodynamic Counselling and

Cognitive Behaviour Therapy

Birkbeck College - University of London

September 2015 – March 2017 Foundation Degree in

Psychodynamic Counselling and Cognitive Behaviour Therapy

Birkbeck College – University of London

Experience

November 2019 to Date: Cognitive behavioural therapist and psychodynamic Counselling, Health City. Assessing and treating adults with depression, anxiety, trauma, additions, relationship problems, work stress, etc.

July 2017 – November 2019-Counsellor – HAGA - Providing counselling support to clients in a service that supports people to tackle the harm brought about by excessive alcohol use to themselves, their families and others around them. I work with clients using psychodynamic counselling or cognitive behaviour therapy depending on the individual preference/circumstance of the client. I also have experience in running support groups for clients which is done as and when I am needed.

February 2015 – July 2017 - Look Ahead – Contract Manager – Managing a 31 bedded hostel for people suffering from varying degrees of mental health issues, some with substance abuse and alcohol issues with a history of homelessness.

February 2012 – February 2015 Certitude – Registered and Supported Living Manager (Harrow) – Providing management support for a cluster of services providing physical and emotional support to people suffering varying degrees of mental health issues. I am au fait with regulatory bodies such as Supporting People and the Care Quality Commission. I managed a staff team of 2 Team Leaders and 10 Support Workers.

December 2002 – August 2005 – Team Leader – Community Housing Association - running a Registered Scheme for 30 adults between the ages of 18 and 65. All residents are long-term sufferers of varying degrees of mental health and substance abuse problems and a history of homelessness. My duties involve the day-to-day running of the project, ensuring proper budgetary controls are kept and met. I also supervised 7 project workers and a deputy manager. I also worked within the regulations of the Commission for Social Care Inspectorate and the Supporting People Programme.

November 2000 – May 2001 - Deputy Manager, Southwark Social Services – working in a residential setting for 12 people with varying degrees of learning disabilities. My duties included the day-to-day running of the project, administrative duties including budgetary controls, staff supervision and representing the service in various review and care planning meetings.

Training Courses Attended

I have attended various in-house training courses. These include the following

- Dealing with people with Personality Disorders and Challenging Behaviours
- First Aid

And many more

I am a keen keyboard player and love to play Chess. I am a confident communicator and a strong believer in the Equality of Opportunities for all.

References will be provided on request